(
"ai_sub_version": "3.5.1",
"generated_at": "2026-08-01T13:34:37.127079",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 9,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 18,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"any_pending": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true,
"max_storage_gb": 18.0
),
"search": (
"qps": 0.3,
"max_length": 4096,
"web_search_tool": "langsearch",
"timeout": 60.0,
"retries": 3,
"min_wait_seconds": 1.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 10.0,
"multiplier": 2.0
),
"validation_buffer_ms": 2000,
"verification_gap_seconds": 60,
"gap_verification_retries": 1,
"gap_verification_ignore_start": true,
"gap_verification_ignore_end": true
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": false,
"fps": 1.0,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": null
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"per_run": 5,
"max_runs": 3,
"multiplier": 2.0,
"min_wait_seconds": 30.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 300
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false,
"progress_bars": true,
"progress_bar_width": 80,
"progress_bar_refresh_seconds": 1.0
)
ときのそら 生誕祭 2025 新衣装お披露目
Tokino Sora Birthday Party 2025: New Costume Reveal
#ときのそらお披露目誕生日2025
#TokinoSoraBirthdayReveal2025
我らの宇宙の始まりは
Our universe's beginning is
触れた瞬間 アララララ
The moment we touched, arararara
はぁ〜、これは困った！
Ahh, this is trouble!
二度ともとにもどらない 大・爆・発！
Never returning to how it was, a massive Big Bang!
そして星が生まれまして
And stars were born
明け方の壱番星は
The morning star at dawn
あなたと出逢った！
Met you!
これは次元を揺るがす 大・発・見！
This is a groundbreaking discovery shaking dimensions!
このままハート打ち上げて どこまでも
Keep launching hearts up to anywhere
たかいそらまで 「めちゃ飛びんださいっ！」
up to the highest sky— "I wanna fly super far!"
さあ スター スタートさあ 届いたこのラブは
Now, start, start, this love that reached you
あなたがなきゃ もう回ってんぞ
If it's not you, it's already spinning
超新星してんぞ
Supernoving!
知っちゃうぞ あなたのハートのディス
I'll find out your heart's dis—
暇なときでいいよみたいな顔して めっちゃめちゃタイト！
Acting like you're free when you're super-duper tight!
ちょっとの反応くれたら喜ばしい てか、こんなの逃すなんてなげかわしい…
I'd be happy for even a little reaction, though letting this slip is regrettable...
我らの星の活動は わりと続いてムモモモ！
Our star's activities keep going on and on!
いやぁ〜、これはスゴイな！ つまりあなたとわたしの創・世・記！
Man, this is amazing! In other words, our genesis!
このままハートあなたごと連れて彼方を目指したら 「めちゃ飛びんじゃったっ！」
Taking you and my heart towards the distance— "I flew super far!"
愛は地球くらいに膨らんでこんなになってんぞ
Love has expanded to the size of the Earth like this
そうさ第三の惑星はこのときのためのスタート！
That's right, the third planet is a start just for this time!
ドゥ ユ アンダ スタ、スタ、スタンド あのさ、わかってる？
Do you under-stand, stand, stand? Hey, do you get it?
ほら目の前にずーっとある 一・等・星！
Look, right before your eyes is a first-magnitude star!
みてろ？ みてろ！
Watch me? Watch me!
このビッグバン気づいて！！
Realize this Big Bang!!
我らの星の活動は
Our star's activities
わりと続いてムモモモモ！
Keep going on and on!
いやぁ〜、これはすごいな！ つまりあなたと私のゾンビ…？
Man, this is amazing! In other words, you and my legend...?
このままハートあなたごと連れて彼方を目指したら
Taking you and my heart towards the distance—
「めちゃ飛びんじゃったっ！」
"I flew super far!"
ああ スター スタートさあ
Ah, start, start,
知ったこのラブはあなたがなきゃ今頃超新星してた…
This love I've come to know would have gone supernova by now if not for you...
してたか…？
Or would it...?
ほら今日まで続いた！
Look, it has lasted until today!
ドゥ ユ アンダ スタ、スタ、スタンド ちゃんとわかっててね
Do you under-stand, stand, stand? Make sure you understand
いっそ光度増して輝く 一・等・星！
A first-magnitude star shining with even more intensity!
あなたと 私で
With you and me
ビッグバンしたいのっ！
We want to make a Big Bang!
愛は地球くらいに膨らんでこんなになってんぞ
Love has expanded to the size of the Earth like this
そうさ第三の惑星はこのときのためのスタート！
That's right, the third planet is a start just for this time!
みんな！今日は お誕生日ライブに来てくれて、ありがとう！
Everyone! Thank you so much for coming to my birthday live today!
最初に聴いて飾った…もとい聴いてもらったのは スタースタースタートでした！
The first song you heard— I mean, the first one you listened to was "Star Star Start"!
みんなコメント見えてるよー。初めての人のいっぱいいっぱいコメントしてってね！
I can see everyone's comments. To those joining for the first time, please leave lots of comments!
最初から、すごい…気合いが入りすぎましたね！
Right from the start, we had... way too much energy!
というわけで、えー今日は私のお誕生日です。
So, um, today is my birthday.
喉が渇きました。あ、すいません、ありがとうございます。
My throat got dry. Oh, um, thank you.
あ、お茶ある。星…
Oh, there's tea. Star...
はい、というわけで、お水美味しいぞ！というわけで、今日のハッシュタグは ときのそらお披露目誕生日2025です。
Right then, water is delicious! So, today's hashtag is #TokinoSoraDebutBirthday2025.
ぜひトレンドにも入れたいので、よければXとかでもつぶやいてください。
We definitely want to get it trending, so please post about it on X if you'd like.
そしてですね、新衣装のお披露目やゲストもたくさん呼んでるので、楽しみにしててね！
And also, we have the new outfit reveal and lots of guests coming, so look forward to it!
今日可愛いしょ？わーい！
I look cute today, don't I? Yay!
そして、見てぬんぬんがね…
And look, Nunnun is...
4段になってるんです。
It's 4 tiers high.
4段になってるのは、あの、毎年増やしてるから読んだんなんですね。
It's 4 tiers because I add one every year, that's why.
てことは来年は5段になるんだな。
That means next year it'll be 5 tiers.
すごい、どんどん積まれていっちゃうね。
Amazing, they're just piling up more and more.
そしてあんきももですね、今回はホログラムでビッグサイズ！
And Ankimo too, this time in hologram, big size!
でか！本当に大きい。
Huge! Really big.
私だけを映すと文字しか映らなかっっていうビッグサイズなんですよね。
If you only film me, it's a big size where only text shows.
おだんごかな？
Is it a dumpling?
そう、おだんごなんですよ。あ、ぬんぬんのことです。
Right, it's a dumpling. Oh, I mean Nunnun.
顔がね、大きくて見えないので、じゃあ、ぬんぬーん！
The face is too big to see, so... Nunnun!
聞こえる？
Can you hear me?
あー、きた！ぬんぬんが来ました！
Ah, it's here! Nunnun has arrived!
というわけで、ぬんぬん乗せてもらってもいいかニャ？
So, Nunnun, is it okay if I ride on you?
いい？うわあ！埋まってるけどね、乗るっていうより。
Really? Whoa! I'm sinking rather than riding.
あーい！
Yay!
ということでこちらがあんきもの顔です。あんきもは ずっとこうやって動いてます。
So this is Ankimo's face, moving around like this.
意外とね、つぶらな瞳なんですけど、ちゃんとね、おめめになってるんですね。素晴らしい。
Surprisingly beady-eyed, but they're proper eyes. Wonderful.
うんうん、うんうん。
Yeah, mm-hmm.
そして、お！みんな！見えてるよー！
And, oh! Everyone! I can see you!
会場のみんな、
Everyone at the venue,
ありがとう！ありがとう！
thank you! Thank you!
見えてるぞー！うわーい！
I can see you! Yay!
うーい！
Yay!
ということで、そんなぬんぬんが、空を飛ばしてくれました。いぇい！
So, Nunnun gave me a ride through the sky. Yay!
というわけで、そんなぬんぬんが下ろしてくれた場所は、さっきと違う場所ですね。
The place Nunnun dropped me off is different from before.
もう1回お水を飲んだら、曲に行きたいかなと思います。
Once I drink some water, I'd like to move on to the song.
いやあ、今日はね、ドキドキなんですよ。うん。
Man, I'm so nervous today. Yeah.
生放送ってね、やっぱドキドキしますよね。
Live broadcasts always make you nervous, right?
さっきまでね、「調子悪い、調子悪い」って言ってたのにね、今全然調子悪くなくなっちゃった。
Until just now I wasn't feeling well, but now I'm totally fine.
こんなだから誰にも心配してもらえないんだ。ふふふ、えへへ。
That's why nobody ever worries about me. Hehe.
というわけで、次の曲、行ってみましょう。2曲続けて聞いてください。
So let's move on to the next song. Please listen to two songs.
♪
[Music]
喜びが舞う春を想う涙の羽
The wings of my tears, thinking of spring where joy dances,
散りゆく花びらとなりあなたのもとへと
become falling petals and head towards you.
風が鳴る度そばにいるよ
Every time the wind blows, I will be by your side.
辿り着けぬ哀しみより寂しさより護るべきは今を生きるあなた
More than sadness or loneliness, what I must protect is you.
生まれ変わったら桜の下でまた逢いましょう
If we are reborn, let's meet again under the cherry blossoms.
きっとその時には笑って永遠を誓おう
I swear that when that time comes, we will smile and pledge eternity.
愛し愛されてこの命は芽吹きそして
Loved and loving, this life buds and blooms,
色褪せない眼差しを胸に舞い散る願い
a persistent gaze becomes a wish dancing in my chest.
あなたに あなたに あなたに ただ逢いたい
To you, to you, to you, I just want to meet you.
降り注ぐ雨音止むまで光はない右と左のツバサは傷つき揺れている
No light until the pouring rain stops, my wings wounded and trembling.
穏やかな日々信じながら愛していると伝えたいと伝えないのは
Believing in peaceful days, I want to say I love you,
忘れてほしい明日を生かすため
so you can forget and live for tomorrow.
生まれ変わったら桜の下でまた逢いましょう待ち焦がれた季節の中で共に歩もう
If we are reborn, let's meet again under the cherry blossoms,
この心を塗り潰した花よあなたに届け誇り高い遠い空で名もなき風に
May the flowers dyeing my heart reach you on the nameless wind.
大切なものはどの時代も変わらないことを人は知りながら過ちをなぜ繰り返す
Important things never change, why do people repeat mistakes?
生まれ変わったら桜の下でまた逢いましょうきっとその時には笑って永遠を誓おう
If we are reborn, let's meet under the cherry blossoms again.
愛し愛されてこの命は芽吹きそして色褪せない眼差しを胸に舞い散る願い
Loved and loving, this life buds and blooms,
あなたに あなたに あなたに ただ逢いたい
To you, to you, to you, I just want to meet you.
喜びが舞う 春を思う 涙の羽
Joy flutters, thinking of spring, feathers of tears.
散りゆく花びらとなり あなたのもとへと
Becoming scattering petals, heading toward your side.
穏やかな日々 信じながら
Believing in peaceful days,
愛していると 伝え たくて
wanting to tell you I love you,
伝えたいのに 伝えられないのは
wanting to tell you, but unable to,
忘れて ほしい 明日 を 生きる ため に
I want to forget, so I can live tomorrow.
生まれ変わったら 桜の下で また逢いましょう
If we are reborn, let's meet again under the cherry blossoms.
待ち焦がれた 季節の中で 共に歩こう
Let's walk together in the season we longed for.
この心を染め抜いた花よ あなたに届け
Oh flower that dyed this heart, reach out to you.
誇り高き 遠い空で 名もなき風に
In the proud, distant sky, on a nameless wind,
大切なモノは いつ の時代も 変わらないこと
what is precious never changes across any era.
人は知りながら 過ちをなぜ繰り返す
People repeat mistakes even while knowing better.
愛し愛されて この命は 芽吹いて咲いて
Loving and being loved, this life buds and blooms.
色褪せない眼差しを 胸に舞い散る願い
A wish dancing in my heart with an unfading gaze.
あなたに あなたに
For you, for you,
あなたに ただ 逢い たい
for you, I just want to meet you.
生まれ変わったら 桜の下で また逢いましょう
If we are reborn, let's meet again under the cherry blossoms.
きっと その時には 笑って 永遠を誓おう
I swear that when that time comes, we'll laugh forever.
愛し愛されて この命は 芽吹いて咲いて
Loving and being loved, this life buds and blooms.
色褪せない眼差しを 胸に舞い散る願い
A wish dancing in my heart with an unfading gaze.
あなたに あなたに あなたに ただ 逢い たい
For you, for you, for you, I just want to meet you.
「死たいなんて言うなよ。」 「諦めて生きろよ。」
"Don't say you want to die." "Live on without giving up."
そんな歌が正しくて馬鹿げてるよな
How foolish it is to say songs like that are correct.
実際自分は死んでもよくて 周りが死んだら悲しくて
In truth, I wouldn't care if I died, but I'd be sad if those around me did,
「それが嫌だから」っていうエゴなんです
so I suppose it's just an ego that says "because I wouldn't like it."
他人が生きてもどうでもよくて 誰かを憎むこともファッションで
Not caring if others live, hating someone as a fashion,
それでも「平和に生きよう」なんて素敵なことでしょう
yet "let's live in peace," what a wonderful thing that would be.
画面の先では誰かが死んで それを嘆いて誰かが歌って
On the other side of the screen, someone dies, lamenting that, someone sings,
それに感化された少年がナイフを持って走った
influenced by that, a boy ran off carrying a knife.
僕らは命に嫌われている 価値観もエゴも押し付けて
We are hated by life itself, forcing our values and egos,
いつも誰かを殺したい歌を 簡単 電波で流した
easily broadcasting songs of wanting to kill someone over radio waves.
僕らは命に嫌われている 軽々しく死たいだとか
We are hated by life itself, thoughtlessly saying we want to die
軽々しく命を見ている 僕らは命に嫌われている
and looking at life carelessly, we are hated by life itself.
お金がないので今日も 一日中惰眠を貪る
I've got no money, so today too I spend the whole day sleeping lazily.
生きる意味なんて見出せず 無駄を自覚して息をする
Without finding any meaning to life, I breathe while realizing it's pointless.
「死にたいなんて言うなよ」
"Don't say you want to die."
「諦めないで生きろよ」
"Live on without giving up."
そんな歌が正しいなんて馬鹿げてるよな
Such songs are so foolish.
実際自分は死んでもよくて周りが死んだら悲しくて
I wouldn't care if I died,
「それが嫌だから」って言うエゴなんです人目が生きてもどうでもよくて誰かを嫌うこともファッションでそれでも平和に生きようなんて素敵なことでしょう画面の先では誰かが死んでそれを嘆いて誰かが歌ってそれに感化された少年がナイフを持って走った僕らは命に嫌われている価値観もエゴも押し付けていつでも誰かを殺したい歌を簡単に電波で流した僕らは命に嫌われている軽々しく死にたいだとか軽々しく命を見ている僕らは命に嫌われているお金がないので今日も一日中惰眠を奏でる生きる意味なんて見出せず無駄を自覚して息をする寂しいなんて言葉でこの傷を表せるものなのかそんな意地ばかり抱え今日も一人ベッドに眠る少年だった僕たちはいつしか青年へ変わっていく年老いていつか枯れ葉のように誰にも知られず朽ちていく不死身の身体を手に入れて一生死なずに生きていくそんなSFを妄想している自分が死んでもどうでもよくてそれでも周りに生きて欲しくて矛盾を抱えて生きていくなんて怒られてしまう正しいものは正しくないさい死にたくないなら生きないで悲しくなるならそれでもいいならずっと一人で笑えよ僕らは命に嫌われている幸福の意味すら分からず生まれ育った環境ばかり憎んで簡単に過去ばかり呪う僕らは命に嫌われているさよならばかりが好きすぎて本当の別れなど知らない僕らは命に嫌われている幸福も別れも愛情も友情も滑稽な夢の戯れで全部カネで買える代物明日死んでしまうかもしれないすべて無駄になるかもしれない朝も夜も春も秋も変わらず誰かがどこで死ぬ夢も明日も何もいらない君がいた生きているならそれでいいそうだ本当はそういうことが歌いたい命に嫌われている結局いつかは死んでいく君だって僕だっていつかは枯れ葉のように朽ちていくそれでも僕らは必死に生きて命を必死に抱えて生きて殺してあがいて笑っては抱えて生きて生きて生きて生きて生きろ
That ego makes me sleep alone tonight.
命に嫌われている
We are hated by life itself.
はい、ということで今聴いてもらったのは
And now, the songs we just heard
「さくらみと」と「命に嫌われている」でした。
were "Sakuramito" and "Inochi ni Kirawarete Iru."
はあ、緊張しすぎて
I was so nervous,
ちょっと何回か止まっちゃった
I almost stopped a few times!
(笑)
(laughs)
リハの方が声出てたよ絶対にね。
My voice came out better on the rehearsal version, definitely!
そうでしょう？みんなそう、え？
Right, everyone?
わあ！今トレンドにいいの？
Oh, is this trending right now?
みんなありがと、おーおーおーおー
Thank you, everyone!
急なテンションの差にビビらないで
Don't scare me with such a sudden mood shift!
ねえ？ねえ？
Right? Right?
めちゃめちゃよかった！ワンコって言わないで、私犬じゃないんだが？
It was super good! Don't call me a dog, I'm not a dog!
ワン！
Woof!
ありがとうございます。
Thank you very much.
これ美味しい。
This is delicious.
ラクザがすごい、ね、ラクザすごいよね！
Rakuza is amazing, right? Rakuza is amazing!
いやあ
Man...
でもさ、まだまだライブは始まったばかりよ。
Well, the live has only just begun!
今日初めて見に来ましたっていう人
To everyone who came to see me for the very first time today,
ぜひ楽しんでってね！
please enjoy yourselves to the fullest!
イエーイ！ごきげん！
Yay! Good spirits!
というわけで、早速次はゲストパートに行っちゃおうかな！
That being said, next up is the guest part!
最初のゲストは、この人だ！
Our first guest is... this person!
はい、ということで最初のゲストはゆいちゃんです！
Well then, our first guest is Yui-chan!
ゆいたーん！
Yay!
そらさん
Sora-san,
声やばい
your voice is crazy!
待って、声やばい
Wait, your voice is crazy...
そらさん、声やばい
Sora-san, your voice is crazy!
えぐい声してて、お誕生日おめでとうございます！
Your voice sounds so rough, Happy Birthday!
ありがとうございます！
Thank you so much!
すいません、本当にこの度はこの度は本当に誠に…誠に申し訳ございませんでした！
I'm so sorry, truly, for this time, truly, sincerely... I'm so, so sorry!
ちょっと良くなってきた？
Have you gotten a bit better?
えっ、何ですか？ ちょっと待って、声出ない
Eh, what is it? Wait a second, my voice isn't coming out.
いや、リハーサルの時の方が声出てた
No, my voice came out better during rehearsals.
何が起きたの？ この数字何があったの？
What happened? What happened to this number?
大事にしよう
Let's cherish it.
いやね、ということでね、体調ね、ちょっとね、喉をね、なんか
Well, you know, so... my physical condition, right... well, my throat, somehow...
さっきまで声出なくなってしまって、本当に申し訳ないです
My voice stopped coming out just a moment ago, I'm truly sorry.
もう、こんなね、晴れ舞台にお誘いいただいたのに、本当に申し訳ないです
Even though you invited me to such a wonderful stage, I'm truly sorry.
いや、本当は今日一緒にね、歌いたかったんですけど…歌いたかった
Well, actually I wanted to sing together with you today... I wanted to.
そうなんです、次に歌う曲なんですけど、限りなく灰色へと歌おうと思ったんですけど、練習したんです
That's right, the next song, I thought about singing 'Kagirinaku Haiiro e', I practiced it.
あのね、去年のさ、3Dになったじゃん、ゆーちゃんが
Um, last year, right, Yu-chan became 3D.
で、ずっとね、去年も呼ぼうと思ってたんだけど、去年はまだ3Dじゃなくって
And all along, I thought about inviting you last year too, but last year you weren't 3D yet.
で、去年からずっとコラボしたいと思ってて、今年の誕生日にはゆーちゃんを呼ぼうって決めてて
And ever since last year I wanted to collaborate, and for this year's birthday I decided to invite Yu-chan.
そんなに思ってくださっていたのに私じゃねえ、寄せれた！
Even though you thought that much of me, I didn't make it... I missed it!
で、そのゆーちゃんに、もっと相応な曲と思ってこの曲を選んだんですよね
And for Yu-chan, thinking it's a fitting song, I chose this song.
私のために選んでくださったのに、何してんだ、この野郎！
Even though you chose it for me, what are you doing, you jerk!
いやね、でも、この状態で、おしゃべりだけでも出てくれるのはとっても嬉しいから
Well, but, in this state, just coming out to chat makes me so happy.
いやいやむしろ、こんなただおしゃべりだけの為に参加させていただいても、本当にありがとうございます！
No no rather, even just participating for this chatting part, thank you so much!
ありがとうございます！
Thank you!
もうだからさ、今度なんか配信とかじゃなくて、動画とか一緒に作ったりしようか
So, next time, instead of streaming, let's make a video together or something.
え、今回のリベンジみたいな感じでさ
Eh, like a revenge for this time.
やりたいです！やりたいです！やります！
I want to do it! I want to do it! Let's do it!
みんなも、見たいよね？見たいよね、ぺちぺち音が聞こえる
Everyone wants to see it too, right? You want to see it, right? I can hear slapping sounds.
ほっぺぺちぺちしてました
I was slapping my cheeks.
いや、本当にこの出演ありがとうございます、嬉しい本当に
No, thank you truly for appearing, I'm really happy.
もう、歌が良すぎて、私ゲスト出る前ちょっと歓喜危ういそうだった
The singing was so good, right before my guest appearance I was almost about to cry.
本当にありがとう！さっき歌われてた歌が良すぎて、本当にはい、感動しました
Thank you so much! The song just sung was so good, really, yes, I was moved.
本番の方が良かったかな？そうだね、もうめちゃくちゃ素敵でした！
Was the actual performance better? That's right, it was super wonderful!
ということでね、次の曲、2人用なんですけど、1人で頑張って歌おうと思うので、是非よろしく…応援しています！
And so, the next song, it's for two people, but I'll do my best to sing it alone, so please... I'm cheering for you!
ありがとうございます！頑張ってください、すいません本当に
Thank you so much! Please do your best, I'm really sorry.
いや全然で、また一緒に遊ぼうね！
No not at all, let's hang out together again!
はい、ぜひ！歌も一緒に歌ったもんね。あ、セリフも振って
Yes, definitely! We sang songs together too. Ah, cue the lines too.
セリフも振る、ありがとう！
Cueing the lines too, thank you!
ありがとうございます！ではまた一緒に話そうね！
Thank you very much! Well then, let's talk together again!
失礼致します。ありがとうございます！頑張ってください！またね！またね！
Excuse me. Thank you very much! Do your best! See you again! See you again!
というわけで、まさかの1人で歌います。聞いてください。限りなく灰色へ
And so, unexpectedly I will sing alone. Please listen. Kagirinaku Haiiro e
才能なんてないことはここで一生泣いているんだろ
Since I have no talent, I've been crying here all my life, haven't I?
目に映った景色の青さが羨しく思っていた
I envied the blue hue of the scenery reflected in my eyes.
路肩に転がる人生アスファルトの温度下がってる
A life rolling by the roadside, the asphalt temperature is dropping.
真夜中を照らす灯りを求めつなぐ電波セカイへと
Seeking the light illuminating midnight, connecting to a world of radio waves...
Rainy Rainy 求めるものだけ描いた
Rainy Rainy, I only drew what I desired.
心閉まった待って! 本当は叫びたいのよ
Closing my heart, wait! I actually want to scream out now.
Rainy Rainy 強くありたいと願った
Rainy Rainy, I wished to be stronger.
声は無情に散って 孤独を奏でる
My voice mercilessly scatters, playing out my loneliness.
有象無象 人の成り 虚勢 心象 人外 物怪みたいなだ
Phantoms, impostors, human forms, bluff, non-human...
虚心坦懐 命宿し あとはぱっぱらっぱな中身なき人間
With an open mind, harboring life, and a hollow human
寄せる期待 不平等な人生 才能もない 大乗 非日常が
Expectations closing in, an unfair life, no talent, extraordinary
闇を祓って 闇を祓って
Exorcise the darkness, exorcise the darkness
夜の帳が下りたら合図だ
Once the veil of darkness descends, that's our cue
相対して 廻る環状戦
Standing face to face, the revolving loop line
戯言などは 吐き捨ていけと
Spit out and discard all nonsense
まだ止めないで まだ止めないで
Don't stop yet, don't stop yet
誰より誇らしく在る 街に生まれしこの正体を
To be prouder than anyone, the true nature born in this town
今はただ呪い呪われた 僕の未来を創造して
Now just imagine my future, cursed and cursing
走って 転んで 消えない痛み抱いては
Running and falling, embracing pain that won't disappear
世界が待ってる この一瞬を
The world is waiting for this one moment
こんな世界へとバイバイバイバイ
Saying goodbye to such a world, bye-bye, bye-bye
滲む思いなぞって描いた
Tracing and drawing blurring thoughts
夢の形に泣いちゃった
I cried over the shape of my dream
いつかできると思ってた
I always thought I could do it someday
だけど現実は残酷だろ
But reality is so cruel, isn't it?
焦りと不安の渦の間に 黒くなって浮かんでる
Floating in dark swirls of impatience and anxiety
退廃的なセンスと曖昧な表現なんちゃって
Decadent sense and ambiguous expression, yeah right
気を衒った奴らのアルスに飲み込まれて消えてく
Swallowed up and disappearing into the artifice of those seeking attention
レイニー レイニー
Rainy, rainy
雨と流れ去ってくのか
Will it wash away with the rain?
肩を慣らして残った
Warming up my shoulders, what remains
冷たい記憶の体温
Is the body temperature of cold memories
レイニー レイニー
Rainy, rainy
雲の隙間から覗いた
Peeking through the gaps in the clouds
光当たって 届いて 体を軽くしたんだ
Light striking, reaching, making my body feel lighter
綺麗事とか プライドとか 語る前に やることやっていけ
Before talking about pretty ideals or pride, just get things done
塞ってしまったのタイロに
Into the closed-off path
焼けた才能を一つ置いてけ
Leave behind your burnt-out talent
ただやったもん勝ちなんだろ 片隅で頷いてる場合じゃないだろ
It's all about who does it first! This is no time to nod in the corner
目を開いて向こう側の灰なのに気付いたってどうしようもないから
Realizing you're on the other side of the ashes with your eyes open changes nothing
それを越したんだって狙ってる ペルソナになって壊されないよ
Aiming to surpass it, become a persona so you won't be broken
私だけ見て愛を伝えて
Look only at me and express your love
こんな世界へとバイバイバイバイ
Saying goodbye to such a world, bye-bye, bye-bye
滲む思いなぞって描いた
Tracing and drawing blurring thoughts
夢の形笑っていた
Laughing at the shape of my dream
燻ってしまったの灰色に
Smoldering into gray
こんな才能なんて借り物
Talent like this is just borrowed
まだ人生終わってないから
My life isn't over yet
諦めんなって誰かの声
So don't give up, someone's voice
見失ってしまったの灰色に気付けなくて今も抗ってる
Unable to notice being lost in gray, I'm still fighting
私だけ見て愛を伝えて
Look only at me and express your love
こんな世界へとバイバイバイバイ
Saying goodbye to such a world, bye-bye, bye-bye
滲む思いなぞって描いた
Tracing and drawing blurring thoughts
夢の形笑っていた
Laughing at the shape of my dream
はーい、皆さん、ありがとうございましたー！
Hi everyone, thank you so much!
いやー一回一回お水を飲まないと、息が切れてしまいますね。
Man, if I don't drink water every time, I'll run out of breath.
はーい、あ、違う違う。反応してしまった。はーいって。
Ha-i, ah, wait, no. I reacted to it. Saying 'ha-i'.
いやーというわけで、ゲストまだまだ見たいよね？ということでどんどん行っちゃいましょうか！
Well then, as for guests, you still want to see more, right? So let's keep going!
続いてのゲストはこの人です！
Our next guest is this person!
富士葵
Fuji Aoi
白い薔薇の花びら ひとつふたつ開けば
If white rose petals open one by one,
あの日の記憶蘇るでしょう
The memories of that day will revive, won't they?
安らぎに照らされて 花を咲かせた夜は
Illuminated by peace, the night that made flowers bloom
甘くせつなく 色づいていく
Is becoming sweet, painful, and colorful
輪廻-ロンド-
Rinne Rondo
光る糸を辿るように
As if tracing a thread of light,
時は静かに流れて
time flows quietly,
満ち引く揺れに添いながら
while accompanying the ebb and flow,
人は生まれ変わる
people are reborn.
あなたの微笑みは　胸を溶かすぬくもり
Your smile is warmth that melts my heart,
どこかで見た　儚い夢のように
like a fleeting dream I saw somewhere.
沈む夕日に　今を切り取られても
Even if the present is cut away by the setting sun,
二人の影は重なっていく
our two shadows overlap.
果てしく長く　限りなく深く　交わった運命のように
Endlessly long, infinitely deep, like an intertwined destiny,
何度もつかんで　何度も失って　やっと巡り合えたこと
grasping again and again, losing again and again, we finally met.
空が地を求め　花が雨を待ち
As the sky seeks the earth, flowers await the rain,
夜が明日を乞うように
and the night yearns for tomorrow,
二つの心が　一つだったこと
the two hearts were once one—
こんなにも求めてたの
I had been searching for it this much.
永い眠り解いて　今宵巡り逢えたら　二人のロンドさ踊りましょう
Breaking our eternal slumber, if we can meet tonight, let's dance our rondo.
過ぎた日々を流すように　月は優しく潤って
As if washing away days gone by, the moon gently moistens,
記憶の先に もう一度　愛しさが溢れた
and once more beyond memories, affection overflowed.
貴方の年月を　二重に歩むなら　影となって守っていたい
If I walk your years alongside you, I want to be your shadow and protect you.
吹き迷う風　二人を遠ざけても
Even if the swirling winds distance us,
信じることを忘れないで
never forget to believe.
宛てない煌めき　儚い揺らめき　彷徨いながらも
Aimless sparkle, fleeting shimmer, even while wandering,
変わらない場所へ　やっとたどり着いたこと
to the unchanging place, we finally arrived.
闇が陽を奪い　嘘が罪に泣き
As darkness robs the sun, lies weep in sin,
過去が未来を裂いていても
and the past tears the future apart,
巡りゆく様に　きっとこの場所を
just like the revolving cycle, surely this place
私は選んでいたの
I had chosen.
果てしく長く　限りなく深く　交わった運命のように
Endlessly long, infinitely deep, like an intertwined destiny,
何度もつかんで　何度も失って　やっと巡り合えたこと
grasping again and again, losing again and again, we finally met.
空が地を求め　花が雨を待ち
As the sky seeks the earth, flowers await the rain,
夜が明日を乞うように
and the night yearns for tomorrow,
二つの心が　一つだったこと
the two hearts were once one—
硝子の花びら　一つ二つ散る時　優しい朝に染まられるでしょう
When glass petals fall one by one, we will be dyed in a gentle morning.
解けて生まれ変わって　あなたの胸に叫ばば
Dissolving and being reborn, if I cry out into your chest,
二人の愛は永遠になる
our love will become eternal.
白い薔薇の花びら　一つ二つ散る時
When white rose petals fall one by one,
優しい朝に染まられるでしょう
we will be dyed in a gentle morning.
解けて生まれ変わって　あなたの胸に叫ばば　二人の愛は永遠になる
Dissolving and being reborn, if I cry out into your chest, our love will become eternal.
はい、ということでね！
Yes, so!
二人目のゲストは、青ちゃんだよー！
Our second guest is Aoi-chan!
みなさーん！富士葵でーす！こんばんはー！
Everyone! It's Fuji Aoi! Good evening!
こんばんはー！
Good evening!
そらちゃん、お誕生日おめでとうございまーす！
Sora-chan, happy birthday!
ありがとー！
Thank you!
呼んでくれてありがとー！もうずっと呼びたくて、ありがとう！
Thank you for inviting me! I've wanted to call you for so long, thank you!
でもさ、コラボとかはしてるけど、こうゆうふうに一緒にやるのは、あれだよね、2年前のね、あそこの記念配信以来。
We've done collabs, but doing it together like this... it's been since that anniversary stream two years ago.
100万人の？　そうそうそうそうそう！
For 1 million subs? Exactly, exactly!
だから、しかも二人で歌うのは相当久しぶりじゃない？
So, singing as a duo is quite a while, isn't it?
もっと前だよ！もっと前だよ！なんか懐かしいって感じがする。
Even longer ago! Even longer ago! It feels so nostalgic.
え、ちょっとさ、ネイル見せよ。
Hey, let's show our nails.
ネイル？
Nails?
青です。
It's blue.
紫です。
It's purple.
頑張って塗ったよー
I worked hard painting it!
ねー、おしゃれしたよー
Right? I dressed up nicely!
いえーい！
Yay!
イエーイ！
いや、あの、あんきもも積み上がって、あんきもじゃないよ
Wait, Ankimommo is stacking up—well, not Ankimommo!
ねぇねぇねぇ、あんきもは１匹ね
Hey, hey, hey, there's only one Ankimommo!
ねぇねぇも積み上がってますけれども
But "Neeneemmo" are stacking up too!
2017年から、8年目？そうだね！なって
Since 2017... Is it year 8? That's right! Becoming...
あのね、数えたんですよ。そらちゃんとの共演を。
You know, I counted. My joint appearances with Sora-chan.
あの、生放送の雑談コラボとかそういうのはなしで、31回！
Excluding live broadcast chatting collabs and stuff... 31 times!
そんなにやってんの！？うわあ！
You've done it that many times?! Wow!
でも、青い調べだから、ちょっとわかんないけど、ざっくり、ざっくりそんな感じだった。
Since it's Ao's research, I'm not totally sure, but roughly, roughly it felt like that.
すごい！本当にね、
Amazing! Really,
いや、だから配信とか、その100万人の お祝いとかも入れたな、もも、もっともっと
yeah, so including streams and 1 million subscriber celebrations and stuff, Momo, even more, even more,
一緒にやらせていただいてるな。バリーだからさ、私たち、私バリーだから、8年目だから
we've been able to do it together. Since we're buddies, you know, we're buddies, it's our 8th year,
青いの顔もだんだんこう、ねぇねぇと一緒に積み上げてくれないかな
Ao's face is also gradually—won't you stack up with Neenee?
怖い怖い！隣とかでいいから。いや、すごいね、だって歴史がさ、ステージにもちりばめられていて
Scary, scary! Next to me is fine. Man, it's amazing, because history is scattered all over the stage too!
ねー！すごいでしょう、めっちゃのんのいってんの、星もあるし。これ、４つそっか４つ４つ、あんきももね、ちゃんとあの、曲のリズムに寄ってこうやってやってんだよね。
Right? Isn't it amazing? Look at Nonno moving so much, and there are stars too. And there are four—four of them—and Ankimommo is moving to the rhythm of the song!
すごい出てる。あの、ゆらゆら動いたりとか、はやっ
It's amazing. Swaying around and moving fast—
はやっ！あんきもも頑張ってるなと思って
Fast! I thought Ankimommo is working really hard.
そう、あんきもめっちゃ頑張ってくれる。どうですか？誕生日の気分？
Yeah, Ankimommo works super hard. How do you feel about your birthday?
いやもうなんかね、さっきまでめっちゃドキドキしてたんだけど、今はこうやってみんなにこう、お祝いされて、めっちゃ嬉しい！
Well, you know, until just now my heart was pounding like crazy, but now receiving everyone's congratulations like this makes me so happy!
みんな、たくさんコメントしてってね！
Everyone, keep posting lots of comments!
すごいよもう、そらちゃんへの愛がね、そらとろさんの、そらちゃんへの愛がもう、あ、ちゃんとはバリーで
It's amazing, the love for Sora-chan, Soratoro-san's love for Sora-chan is already—ah, properly as buddies,
コメントからよろしくお願いします！
from comments, please treat us well!
いっぱいコメントしてよ！いっぱいつぶやいてよ！
Post lots of comments! Tweet lots!
青いのもこのあとも見守っているからね！やったー！
Ao will be watching over you after this too! Yay!
またそうね。あ、あと新曲ね。あ、そんな趣味にしてるから。遊ばね！遊ばね！またね！ありがとう！頑張って！
See you again. Ah, also the new song. Ah, we're making it a hobby. Let's play! Let's play! See you! Thank you! Good luck!
じゃあね。バイバイ。何その…予想外すぎる。というわけで、相変わらず仲良しのあおちゃんでした。
Bye-bye. Bye-bye. What is that... completely unexpected. And so, that was Ao-chan, as friendly as ever.
それでは続いてのゲストに行きましょう。続いてのゲストはこの人です！
Now then, let's move on to the next guest. The next guest is this person!
信じてた 信じられた その全てを
I believed, I was believed in—all of it,
今始めよう
let's begin it now.
不器用なこの勇気は コンプレックス・イメージュ
This clumsy courage is a complex image.
乾いた風が 追いかける波のように
Like the parched wind chasing waves,
そっと背中を押す気がした
it felt like it gently pushed me from behind.
耳をすませば ざわめくローフレキシシー
If I listen closely, a bustling low frequency...
新しい その場所への
To that new place,
扉を開け放て
throw open the door!
切なくて愛おしいほど 想いは時空を超えて
So painful and dear, my feelings transcend time and space.
Together ずっと 心はそばにある
Together, my heart is always by your side.
大切なあの日に溜まりが 刹なに散りゆく景色
The accumulation of that precious day, a scenery scattering in an instant.
今すべての力を与え賜え
Grant me all your power now.
僕は瞳をそらさずに 傷も涙も真実も....
I will not look away from wounds, tears, or reality...
暖かい その雨が 透明なら
If that warm rain is transparent,
力となり
it becomes strength.
もしそれが 深紅ならば コンプレックス・イメージュ
If it is deep crimson, a complex image.
手探りの道 絡み合うラビリンス
A groping path, an intertwined labyrinth.
信じてた 信じられた その全てを 今始めよう
I believed, I was believed in—let's begin all of that now.
不器用なこの勇気は コンプレックス・イメージ
This clumsy courage is a complex image.
乾いた風が 追いかける波のように
The parched wind, like a wave of pursuit,
そっと背中を押す気がした
felt like it softly pushed me from behind.
耳をすませば ざわめくローフレケーシー
A noisy low frequency, if I listen with clear ears,
新しい その場所への 扉を開け放て
throw open a new doorway to that place.
切なくて愛おしいほど 想いは時空を超えて
Unbearable feelings of love transcend space and time.
Together ずっと 心はそばにある
Together, our hearts will always be here.
大切なあの陽だまりが 刹那に散りゆく景色
That precious sunlit ground dissolved in an instant.
今すべての力を与え賜え
Please grant me all my power now.
僕は瞳をそらさずに 傷も涙も真実も……
I won't avert my eyes; not from wounds, tears, or reality...
温かい その雫が 透明なら力となり
If that warm droplet is clear, it becomes strength.
もしそれが 深紅ならば コンプレックス・イメージ
If it is dark crimson, a complex image.
切なくて愛おしいほど 想いは時空を超えて
Feelings so poignant and dear transcend space and time.
Together ずっと 心はそばにある
Together, our hearts are always side by side.
大切なあの陽だまりが 刹那に散りゆく景色
That precious patch of sunlight is a scenery scattering in an instant.
今すべての力を与え賜え
Grant me all your strength now,
僕は瞳をそらさずに 傷も涙も真実も……
I won't avert my eyes from wounds, tears, or reality...
切なくて愛おしいほど 想いは時空を超えて
Feelings so poignant and dear transcend space and time.
はい！聞いていただいたのは
Yes! The song you just heard
「コンプレックス・イメージ」でした！
was "Complex Image"!
そして、ゲストに来ていただきました！
And we have a special guest joining us!
綾堎さんです！
Ayane-san!
綾堎でーす！そらともの皆さん、初めまして！
Ayane here! Nice to meet you, Soratomos!
綾堎です！
I'm Ayane!
今日は来ていただいて、本当に本当にありがとうございます！
Thank you so much for coming today!
ありがとうございます！
Thank you so much!
嬉しすぎてもうテンションが上がってしまっていますが！
I'm so happy, my excitement is through the roof!
私もです！
Me too!
あ、本当ですか！ありがとうございます！
Oh, really? Thank you!
ありがとうございます！
Thank you!
今回綾堎さんに来ていただいたのは
The reason we invited Ayane-san today...
あの、私、なんと、恐れ多くも、なんと「コンプレックス・イメージ」をカバーさせていただきまして！
...is because I had the honor of covering "Complex Image"!
で、ありがとうございます！
And thank you so much!
それに反応していただいたのがとても嬉しくて
I was so happy when you reacted to it,
ぜひぜひコラボで歌わせていただけたら嬉しいなと思って、お呼びいたしました！
so I invited you hoping we could sing it together!
ありがとうございました！
Thank you very much!
いや、来てくれるなんて思っていなくてもう時々が止まらないんですけども！
I didn't think you'd actually come, my heart hasn't stopped pounding!
私もです！
Me too!
今すごい心拍数が上がってます！
My heart rate is soaring right now!
本当に、本当に素敵な歌声で、もう私ずっとこうやって聞いてよっかなって途中で思っちゃいました！
Your singing voice is truly wonderful. I caught myself wanting to just listen!
いやいや、一緒に歌っていただいてありがとうございます！
No, no, thank you for singing with me!
いや、なんかライブでこういうふうに一緒に歌えるとは思っていなかったので、
I honestly never expected to be able to sing together like this at a live show,
えと、どうでしょう、こ、こういう大きいステージで一緒に、歌うのは嬉しいです！
so how is it... singing together on such a big stage? I'm so happy!
嬉しいです。あの、そらさんは横浜アリーナが目標なんですよね！
I'm so happy. Sora-san, your goal is Yokohama Arena, right?
はい！
Yes!
はい。
Yes.
いつか、その夢が叶ったときに、
Someday, when that dream comes true,
ご一緒できたら嬉しいです！
I'd be so happy to join you!
え、いいんですか？
Eh, really? Is that okay?
いいんですか？いいんですか？
Is it? Is it really?
はい！
Yes!
約束します！
I promise!
また歌ってくれるんですか？
Will you sing with me again?
はい、もちろん です。とっても嬉しいです。
Yes, of course. I'm so happy.
もう本当に、ずっとずっと聞いていた曲で、
Truly, I've been listening to this song forever,
他の曲もめちゃくちゃ聴いているので…嬉しいです。ありがとうございます。
and I listen to all your other songs too... I'm so happy. Thank you.
本当に大好きな方に、こう、チェキ会に来ていただけて、
Truly, having someone I love so much come to my cheki session,
私感謝でいっぱいです。
I am filled with gratitude.
今後ともよろしくお願いいたします。
Look forward to working with you in the future.
また、なんかコラボとかできたらとっても嬉しいなと思います。
I'd be so happy if we could do a collab again sometime.
ぜひよろしくお願いいたします。
I'd love that, please look forward to it.
よろしくお願いいたします。
Please look forward to it.
改めまして、そらさんお誕生日おめでとうございます！ありがとうございます！
Once again, Sora-san, happy birthday! Thank you so much!
と いうことで、本日はやねさんに来ていただきました！本当に本当にありがとうございます！
So, today we had Yane-san come join us! Thank you so, so much!
ありがとうございます！
Thank you so much!
緊張した〜
I was so nervous~
緊張したよ。
I was so nervous.
みんなにも緊張が伝わっててよね。
My nervousness probably got across to everyone too.
緊張もうまく言えな…
I can't even say "nervous" right...
あっ、トレンド1位になったの！
Ah, we reached #1 on trending!
ありがとうございます！
Thank you so much!
と いうわけで、あの…お誕生日配信も…
So, um... the birthday stream too...
終盤に近づいてきたんですけども、えっと…
is coming close to the end, but... um...
いや、感無量すぎて…何も言えない。
Oh, I'm just too overwhelmed with emotion... I can't say anything.
でも、まだ、まだまだ先があるよね！
But we still, still have more to come, right!
みんな、新衣装見たいよね！
Everyone, you want to see the new outfit, right!
と いうわけで、新衣装お披露目の時間だよ！
So, it's time to reveal the new outfit!
みんな、準備はいい？
Everyone, are you ready?
いくよ！せーの！
Here we go! Ready, set!
どう？ちょっと見えた？
How was that? Did you catch a glimpse?
ちょっと見えた？ちょっと見えたよね！
Did you catch a glimpse? You saw a bit, right!
でも、しか見えない。
But you can only see so much.
さあ、おめでとうみんな、ありがとう。
Now, congratulations everyone, thank you.
みんな、見たいって言って！
Everyone, say "I want to see it!"
せーの！
Ready, set!
もっともっと見たい見たい！
We want to see more and more!
聞こえないぞ！見たい！
I can't hear you! We want to see it!
あっ、素晴らしいみんな！では行きますよ！
Ah, wonderful everyone! Here we go!
3、2、1、オープン！
3, 2, 1, open!
はい、ということでどうかな？今回の新衣装です！
So, what do you think? This is my new outfit!
なんとね、これね、あの、テーマが…買って貰えてて…なんて思うテーマ？
You know, the theme for this is... I was told... what kind of theme do you think?
読みますね。モノトーン絶対領域パンツ。
Let me read it. Monotone absolute territory pants.
どういうこと！？どういうことー！
What does that mean!? What does that mean!
というわけで、今回はですね、ちょっとショートヘアに憧れちゃいまして、
So, this time, I've been longing for short hair,
私、ちょっとショートヘアのウィッグを…手に入れちゃいました。
so I got my hands on a short hair wig.
どう？ショートヘア初めてだからちょっと緊張してるんだけど、
How is it? It's my first time with short hair so I'm a bit nervous,
似合うかな？似合うかな？
does it suit me? Does it suit me?
どういうこと？なんてテーマだ。多分これが絶対領域ってことなんじゃないかな。
What does that mean? What kind of theme is that? I guess this is what "absolute territory" means.
でね、他にもいろんなものがあるんですけど、それは配信後のアフターライブメンバー限定で見せちゃおうかなって思ってるから、ぜひそっちも見たいなって人、メンバーに会いに来てくれると嬉しいよ。
And you know, there are various other things too, but I'm thinking of showing those in the member-only after-live stream, so I'd be so happy if those who want to see that come check out the membership.
と言うわけで、新衣装で歌っていこうかなって思います！
So, I thought I'd sing in my new outfit!
ショート似合ってるかな？ドキドキしちゃう。
Does the short hair suit me? I'm getting all nervous.
行きますよー！
Here we go!
エレクトリカル・サーフィン！
Electrical Surfin'!
エレクトリカル・サーフィン サーフィンとか
Electrical Surfin' Surfin' and...
ジャンプとか知ってる人は一緒に言ってね！
If you know the jumps and stuff, say it together!
前略、電子の海は今日も 晴れ、時々雪、ところによりポペ
Dear me, the electronic sea today is sunny, occasionally snow, with parfait here and there.
前人未踏のテラバイト島で まだどこかのあなたを待機中
On the untrodden terabyte island, waiting for you from somewhere else.
偶然だって必然のうち 送受信は見えない糸でしょ
Even a coincidence is part of inevitability, signal transmission and reception are invisible threads, right?
断然こっちがしっくりくるから
Definitely, this side feels more right.
Enter×Space で Escape
Enter×Space to escape.
The Boooom! ここは0と1の楽園
The Boooom! Here is a paradise of 0s and 1s.
The Boooom! 広く深い世界から見つけて
The Boooom! Find it from a wide and deep world.
エレクトリカル・サーフィン サーフィン こちらに来て来て
Electrical Surfin' Surfin' Come on, come over here.
好みも狂いもいただけます
I'll take whatever you like, whether good or crazy.
サーフィン サーフィン 手と手とってって
Surfin' Surfin' Holding hands, taking hands.
白昼夢中 夢中で踊り明かしましょう
Daydreaming, let's dance the night away in a trance.
攻略！電子の海は今日も 赤、青、緑でとにかくいっぱいっぱい
Conquest! The electronic sea today is full of red, blue, and green, packed to the brim.
悠々自適のテラバイト島で お待たせのいつもの開始中
On the leisurely terabyte island, the usual long-awaited activity is starting.
だらしなさこそが至福の時でしょ のんびりでくだらんでだらだらで行こう
The absurdity is the time of supreme bliss, right? Let's go leisurely, loafing around.
Command×Delete で Respawn
Command×Delete to respawn.
The Boooom! ここは雲の向こうの未来
The Boooom! Here is the future beyond the clouds.
The Boooom! 狭く暗いブラウザじゃ物足りないの
The Boooom! A narrow and dark browser isn't satisfying enough.
エレクトリカル・サーフィン サーフィン こちらに来て来て
Electrical Surfin' Surfin' Come on, come over here.
酸いも甘いも忘れてさ
Forget about both acidity and sweetness.
サーフィン サーフィン 手と手とってって
Surfin' Surfin' Holding hands, taking hands.
白昼夢中 夢中にするわ 覚えてて
Daydreaming, I'll make you obsessed, remember that.
エレクトリカル・サーフィン サーフィン こちらを見て見て
Electrical Surfin' Surfin' Look, look over here.
空に輝く奇跡の輪
The circle of miracles shining in the sky.
サーフィン サーフィン 手と手とってって
Surfin' Surfin' Holding hands, taking hands.
Welcome to 夢中で飛べ！飛べ！ 飛べ！飛べ！飛べ！飛べ！
Welcome to, fly in a trance! Fly! Fly! Fly! Fly! Fly!
エレクトリカル・サーフィン サーフィン こちらをみてみて
Electrical Surfin' Surfin' Look, look over here.
宵に輝く奇跡の輪
The circle of miracles shining in the evening.
サーフィン サーフィン 手と手とってって
Surfin' Surfin' Holding hands, taking hands.
Welcome to 夢中で止め！止め！ 止め止め止め止め！
Welcome to stop in a trance! Stop stop stop stop!
エレクトリカル・サーフィン サーフィン こちらに来て来て
Electrical Surfin' Surfin' Come on, come over here.
酸いも甘いも頂きます
I'll take both the sweet and sour.
サーフィン サーフィン 手と手とってって
Surfin' Surfin' Holding hands, taking hands.
白昼夢中 夢中で踊り明かしましょう
Daydreaming, let's dance the night away in a trance.
はい、ということでありがとうございましたー！
Phew, so thank you very much!
いやあ、盛り上がる曲いっぱい踊れるようなね、イメージで
Man, I made the new outfit with the image of songs that get you hyped...
新衣装を作ったので、次のゲストパートでもどんな感じになるかなっていうのを見ていこうと思います。
so let's see how it looks in the next guest part as well.
次が最後のゲストパートです！
The next is the final guest part!
告知を見てくれた人ならわかるよね？
If you saw the announcement, you know who it is, right?
この人たちです！
It's these people!
儒烏風亭らでん / 轟はじめ
Juufutei Raden / Todoroki Hajime
誰もが突然に始まった デタラメなシナリオの上で
Everyone is suddenly starting on a nonsensical scenario.
それは映画のような まるで映画のような どこにでもあるストーリー
It's like a movie, just like in the movies, a story found anywhere.
間違いだらけの道のりだ 丸付けられるのはいくつだ
It's a road full of mistakes, how many can be marked correct?
何が良くないのか どこが良くないのか そこまで教えてくれよ
What's not good? What's wrong with it? Tell me that much.
明け方の妄想 貴重な逃避行と 勘違いの英雄ごっこ もう渋滞してんだ
The delusions at dawn, a precious getaway, acting as the misunderstood hero, we're already in traffic.
どうしようもないどうしようもないよな こんなはずじゃなかったよなって
I can't help it, I can't do anything about it. It wasn't supposed to turn out like this.
どんなはずだったんだよなって 思えば思うほど いやこれじゃないない
What was I supposed to expect? The more I think about it, no, this isn't it.
ハマり悪いよな 向いてないな 今すぐ辞めてしまうか
It's a bad habit, I'm not suited for this, should I just quit right now?
そりゃないない いつになれば僕は 主人公になれるんだろうな
That's not gonna happen, when will I ever become the main character?
足りなくなって笑ったり 増えた荷物数えては泣いたり
Laughing when it's not enough, crying counting extra baggage.
期待するほどでもなくがっかり 責めることすらできず悩んだり
Disappointed it wasn't as expected, troubled because I can't even blame anyone.
爛々と輝く街の灯り 散々だって顔の通りすがり
The city lights shining brilliantly, passing by with a face saying it's all over.
さてどうしようか もう一度 いやこれじゃないない
Now what should I do? Let's do it again, no, this isn't it.
ハマり悪いよな 向いてないな
It's a bad habit, I'm not suited for this...
誰もが突然に始まった
Everyone started all of a sudden
デタラメなシナリオの上で
on a nonsensical scenario.
それは映画のような まるです映画のような
It's like a movie, just like in the movies,
どこにでもあるストーリー
a story that's found anywhere.
間違いだらけの道のりだな
It's a path full of mistakes,
丸投げされるのはいくつだ
how many things are just dumped on us?
何が良いのか
What is good?
何処が良いのか分からない
Where is it good? I don't know,
そこまで教えてくれよ
so tell me that much.
明け方の妄想
Delusions at dawn,
貴重な逃避行と
a precious getaway,
勘違いの英雄ごっこ
and a delusional hero game.
もう鬱屈してんだ
I'm already depressed,
どうしようもこうしようもないよな
there's nothing I can do about it.
これじゃないない
This isn't it,
あまり悪いよな
it's pretty bad, right?
むいてないない
It's not off,
今すぐやめてしまえば
if I just quit right now...
でも何万回も糸繰り返した
But I've repeated it tens of thousands of times,
明日に期待してしまおうか
hoping for tomorrow once again.
主役はボクだけだろう
I must be the only protagonist, right?
明け方が来たの
Dawn has arrived,
薄気味の遠飛行 勘違いの英雄ごっこ
a creepy distant flight, a delusional hero game.
もう渋滞してんだどうしようも
We're already in traffic, what should we do?
もうないような
There's nothing left.
あの頃は確かにあったんだ
Back then, it was definitely there,
描き出したものがあったんだ
something I had drawn out.
いつの間にか僕は
Before I knew it, I...
誰もが突然に始まった
Everyone started all of a sudden
デタラメなシナリオの上で
on a nonsensical scenario.
何かを演じるの? 誰かを演じるの?
Are you playing something? Playing someone?
そんなわけがないだろ
There's no way that's true.
まだこれじゃ
This still isn't...
まだここじゃないない
We're still not here yet.
終わりじゃないから
Because it's not over,
むいてないない
it's not off.
だから書き換えてしまえよ
So go ahead and rewrite it!
ほら大体 いつもいつでも
See, mostly, always and forever,
きっと主役はボクだけだろう
surely I am the only protagonist.
いつのか日かバイバイ
Someday, it'll be bye-bye,
終わりは来るから
because the end is coming.
拍手喝采 笑顔でカーテンコール
Applause and cheers, a curtain call with a smile.
変えたい未来はここにあった
The future I wanted to change was right here.
思うままに好きなように これはそうだ
As I wish, just the way I like it—yes, this is it.
最底辺から駆け上がった
I ran up from the very bottom,
映画のようなストーリー
a story just like in a movie.
はい、ということで、最後のゲストは
Yes, so, our final guests are...
はじめちゃんと、ラデちゃんのと
Hajime-chan and Laplace-chan!
ラデハジコンビ!
The "Rade-Haji" duo!
イェーイ!
Yay!
ほら、じゃあまずはそらごちょん バンチョー、(と)きのそら、はじめちょー!
Come on, first Sora-gochon, Bancho, Tokino Sora, Hajime-cho!
はい! 10って…(笑) 全員滑らない! 10って、ラデってございます!
Yes! Ten... (laughs) Everyone's slipping! Ten, it's Rade!
イェーイ!
Yay!
そして先輩、お誕生日おめでとうございます!
And Senpai, happy birthday!
そして、新衣装めちゃいい!
Also, the new outfit is amazing!
やったー!
Yay!
え、ぜひちょっと縮小、なのと撮りたいな、ちょもんなしけど。
Uh, I'd definitely want to take a smaller one, or something like that, even without Chomo.
あ、じゃあポーズ、手持ちカメラの
Ah, then let's pose with a handheld camera!
え、ちょ、ちょ、ちょ、なんで先輩が撮られるの?
Eh, wait, wait, why is Senpai getting her picture taken?
ちょ、ちょ、カメラマンになろうじゃないですか!
Wait, wait, let's be the cameramen!
カメラマンになるんじゃないですよ! 先輩を撮るんですよ!
We're not becoming cameramen! We're taking pictures of Senpai!
かわいいな!
So cute!
じゃあ初めから、ポーズして、なんかシチャったり。
Then from the beginning, let's strike a pose and do something.
ちょら先輩の、チェキティっぽい。
It's like Chora-senpai's cheki-tī style.
チェキティっぽいのみたいな。
Something like a cheki-tī look.
おお、いいですね! チェキティ!
Oh, that's nice! Cheki-tī!
この、このラインがいいですね。このラインが。
This line is nice. This line.
シンプルな衣装だからこそ映えるね。
Because it's a simple outfit, it really pops.
おお、え、ほらポージング。この絶対領域の部分ちょもも。
Oh, eh, look, the posing. This absolute territory part, Chomomo.
あら! いいですね!
Oh! That's great!
すごい、なんか初号なんだろ、ベルトみたいな感じになってて。
Amazing, it looks kind of like... what is it, a belt-like style.
めちゃめちゃ素敵ね!
It's super lovely!
素敵やん!
It's wonderful!
じゃ、ちょっとラデインからも、ちょっと見返り美人のポーズなんて、してらってもいいですか?
Then, Radein, can you also strike a looking-back beauty pose?
お、やった!
Oh, you did it!
めっちゃかわいい!
Super cute!
これには、澁川諸信のもにっこりですよ。
Even Shibusawa Moronobu would be smiling at this.
澁川のもの? (笑)
Shibusawa's? (laughs)
見返り美人の、見返り美人の人。
The looking-back beauty person.
すっごい。
Amazing.
みんなスクショできた? できちゃったかな?
Did everyone take screenshots? Were you able to?
よし!
Great!
なんか髪型も、脇ピタッとしてたから。脇が。
Also the hairstyle, her armpits were pressed close. Her armpits.
あ、ちょ、先輩のワンキグ! っていうこと?
Ah, wait, Senpai's wankigu! Is that it?
え、見えちゃった?
Eh, could you see it?
めっちゃいい!
Super good!
え、じゃあ3人でも撮りたい! え、いくすか?
Uh, then I want to take one with all three of us too! Eh, shall we go?
じゃあ!
Then!
キャプチャー!
Capture!
髪型 ショート同士? あ、ほんとだ! おっそろい!
Hairdos, both short? Ah, that's right! Matching!
服装もおそろいだし。
And our outfits match too.
ひとりだけ緊張感バグった人が混ざってますね
One person's tension is totally bugged out here.
なんてこと…初めてじゃあない？
No way... isn't this a first?
あ、ちょうどいい。
Ah, perfect.
ちょうどいいね。
Yeah, perfect.
確かに。えっちやん。
True. So lewd.
というわけで、二人と一緒に歌えてとっても嬉しかったし、
So, I was so happy to sing together with these two,
これからも仲良くして欲しいよ。
and I hope we can keep getting along well.
やったー！よろしくお願いします！
Yay! Thank you so much!
お邪魔しました。
Thanks for having us.
ありがとうございました！皆さんもお邪魔しました！
Thank you very much! Thanks to everyone too!
ありがとうございました！ちゅきちゅき！
Thank you so much! Chu-ki chu-ki!
じゃ、我々は、我々は。
Well, as for us, as for us.
では、またみなさん。ぽっぽ、ぽっぽっぽっぽっぽ！
Well then, everyone, see you. Poppo!
その去り方は斬新すぎる…
That way of leaving is way too novel...
あん肝の中に消えてっちゃったよ。
She just disappeared inside Ankimo.
はーー！
Haーー!
ということで、ライブも終盤に近づいてきましたが、
So, the live is nearing its climax, but
最後まで盛り上がっていこうーー！
let's get hyped all the way to the endーー!
次の曲を聞いてください。「アンデッド」。
Please listen to the next song. "UNDEAD".
Unhappy? 悩める人の子よ
Unhappy? Oh troubled child of man,
Unlucky? 人成らざる者も
Unlucky? Even non-human beings,
Be happy 怯まず目指せよ
Be happy, aim without flinching.
生きているんだし目を逸した過去も
You're alive, so even the past you looked away from
退屈な未来もカウンセリング
And that boring future are being counseled.
やれやれ古今東西ピースピース
Good grief, everywhere, peace peace.
Unhappy? Unlucky? Be happy! Undead
ねぇねぇねぇねぇなんだかどうして戦ってるようなそんな気がするの
Hey hey hey, somehow it feels like I'm fighting someone
触れられない触れたくない過去の自分自分自分自分ともうとうとに死んでる透明な亡霊と対決
A showdown with a transparent ghost from my past.
幼くて痛い記憶の奥怨念?もう居ないのにあれ?
Deep inside painful childhood memories, a grudge?
そっちが良い?アイロニね透かされているのは現在の自分?ナンセンス
Which is better? Irony, isn't it? Nonsense.
消えないレットスYes要はコンプレックス
An indelible red-to-yes, a complex.
取り憑かれているみたい巻き付いたまま離れない在りし日の自分 Undead
My former self wrapped tightly, Undead.
死んじないお前とお前の連鎖
You won't die, you and your chain.
生きていることとは変わり続けることだ
To be alive is to keep changing on and on.
不幸に甘んじて満足するなよ幸せになろうとしないなんて卑劣だ
Don't settle for unhappiness, don't be a coward.
この世この世は奇怪奇怪ファンタジー
This world is one bizarre fantasy.
次は鬼が出るか蛇が出るか出会って遭ってようやく始まる物語さ
Meeting and encountering, the story finally begins.
ああ人か化け物か閑話休題
Human or monster, but I digress.
ピースピース Past & future Can't change the past
Peace peace, Past & future Can't change the past
Past & future Run for the future カットインなんだかどうして
Past & future Run for the future, cut in.
未来になんぞ何の希望もない期待出来ないような気がして
Feeling like there's no hope for the future.
もう随分生きている既視感とテンプレで食傷
Living long enough, suffering from déjà vu.
素敵な出来事の気配もない残念積もった経験の因果
No sign of wonderful events, accumulated karma.
形骸化された神話と退屈な進化要は刺激が欲しいんだ
Mythology and boring evolution, I want stimulation.
飽きちゃった慣れちゃったなんて整えていくガイダンス
Got bored, got used to it, guidance organizing things.
増えるコンプライアンス覆されていくみたい吸い尽くして
Increasing compliance, sucking it all dry.
あれもこれもどれも同じ味がする Undead
This, that, and everything else taste the same, Undead.
死んじないお前とお前の連鎖何時の世も過去も未来も現在にあるんだ
Your past and future are in the present.
生きていることを愚直に果てせよ目指せハッピーエンド
Fulfill your life honestly, aim for a happy ending.
Undead死んじないお面に言っているんだよ
Undead, I'm telling you who won't die.
幸せを諦めてしまうような人であれただ苦しみに慣れて耐えているだけじゃ死んでいるも同然
Just enduring suffering is practically being dead.
Unhappy? 悩める人の子よ
Unhappy? Oh troubled child of man,
Unlucky? 人成らざる者も
Unlucky? Even non-human beings,
Be happy 怯まず目指せよ
Be happy, aim without flinching.
生きているんだし目を逸した過去も
You're alive, so even the past you looked away from
退屈な未来もカウンセリング
And that boring future are being counseled.
やれやれ古今東西ピースピース
Good grief, everywhere, peace peace.
Past & future Can't change the past
Past & future Run for the future
どこでどうして皆生きているんだろう
Where and why is everyone living?
そんな気がしてもう随分行ってる
It feels like I've gone so far already.
ぎこちないテンプレートで食傷
Suffering from indigestion with awkward templates.
素敵な出来事の気配もない
No sign of wonderful events.
積み重ねた経験の因果乖離かされた神話と退屈な進化
Accumulated karma and boring evolution.
よもや生き急いでんな飽きちゃった慣れちゃったなんてとことんクライマックス
Got bored, got used to it, what a climax.
燃えるコンプライアンス踏襲されてるみたい
Burning compliance, being followed.
泣きついたまままだ離れない
Still crying and won't let go.
愛しい身の自分 Undead
My beloved self, Undead.
死んじないお前と前の連鎖
You won't die, you and the previous chain.
泣いてることも忘れてるずっと
I've even forgotten I was crying all this time.
幸せになろうとしないなんて狂いだ
Not trying to be happy is madness.
この世この世は一期一会ファンタジー
This world is a once-in-a-lifetime fantasy.
次は鬼が出るか蛇が出るか出会って遭ってようやく始まる物語さ
Meeting and encountering, the story finally begins.
ああ人か化け物か閑話休題
Human or monster, but I digress.
ピースピース Past & future Can't change the past
Peace peace, Past & future Can't change the past,
Past & future Run for the future
人形と心にいつも礼儀ごと
Always polite to dolls and hearts.
生き抜くこの化物ばかりの物語
Living through this story full of monsters.
愛しい身の自分 Undead
My beloved self, Undead.
はい、ということで、「UNDEAD」歌いましたー！
So, I sang "UNDEAD"!
今回も振り付けを使っていただいて頑張って歌いましたが、みんなどうだったかな？
I worked hard using the choreography, how was it everyone?
どうだったかな？
How was it?
いい感じだったかな？
Was it a good vibe?
いや、ちょっとね、細かくて難しかったんですけど、でも楽しく歌えたし、みんながね見てくれててとっても嬉しいです。
It was a bit tough, but I had fun and I'm so happy you watched.
というわけで、まだ最後にお披露目はあるんですが、その前に、お知らせが2つあります。
Before the final reveal, I have two announcements.
まずは、こちら！
First is this!
ときのそら誕生日記念2025グッズでーす！
Tokino Sora Birthday Commemoration 2025 Goods!
おめめん！
Omemen!
出てくれてる気がする
I feel like they're coming out!
順番に紹介していくよ！
I'll introduce them in order!
まずはこちら！
First is this one!
「夢のそらばワンマン」ファブリックポスター！
"Yume no Soraba One-man" Fabric Poster!
私が参加してるワンシーンを切り取った物凄いのファブリックポスターです。
A fabric poster featuring a memorable scene from my solo live!
紙のポスターと違って折れたりする心配もないですし
Unlike paper posters, you don't have to worry about it creasing,
長く飾ってくれるかなというこで
and I hope you'll display it for a long time.
お部屋のサイズに合わせてね、折りたたんだりして飾ることもできると思うので
You can even fold it to fit your room's size to display it,
ぜひぜひみんな部屋に飾ってね！
so please, everyone, hang it in your room!
続いては、こちら！
Next is this!
そらとおそろい2wayネックレス！
Sora-to-Osoroi 2-Way Necklace!
今回の新衣装でもしてるネックレスのおそろっちが作りたいなと思って
I wanted to make a matching necklace like the one in my new outfit,
おそろっちのものを用意しました！
so I prepared a matching one for you!
ただね、ネックレスはしないよって人のために、ちょっとチャーム部分を取り外しすることができる2way仕様になってまして
However, for those who don't wear necklaces, it features a 2-way design where you can detach the charm part,
バッグとかにワンポイントでもつけて一緒におそろっちっていうふうにできるようにしました！
so you can attach it as a cute accent to your bag and match with me!
そして続いては、こちら！
And next is this!
そらのバンダナハンカチ！
Sora's Bandana Handkerchief!
おそろいからのハンカチ。今回はね、みんなとおそろっちっていうのをちょっとテーマに作ってみました。
A matching handkerchief! This time, the theme is matching with everyone.
シンプルなデザインなので日常でも使えますし
It's a simple design for everyday use,
でもちょっとロゴも入ってるのでとっても可愛いかなと思います。
and with the subtle logo, it's super cute.
シンプルでいつも持ち歩きやすく、でもおそろいにもできる。
Simple and easy to carry around, yet still matching.
ちょっとね、みんなバンダナはしないかなと思ってハンカチにしてみました！
I thought people might not wear bandanas, so I made it a handkerchief!
みんなで私を持ち歩いてね！
Carry me around with you, everyone!
そして続いては、こちら！
And next is this!
いつも一緒おでかけぬいぐるみバッグ！
Always Together Outing Plush Bag!
こちらはパーカー衣装の私が乗ったぬんぬん型のポーチを開けると、あんきも柄のバッグが出てくるぬいぐるみバッグということで
This is a plush bag where opening the Nun-nun pouch featuring my hoodie outfit reveals an Ankimo-patterned bag.
なんかぬいぐるみのキーホルダーの感覚でこう一緒にお散歩ことか鞄につけるみたいな
It feels like a plush keychain, so you can take it on walks or attach it to your bag.
作ることもできるし、持ち運べるし、なんかグッズとか買い食いしちゃったってときに入るかなってときに
You can carry it around, and if you buy some snacks and need extra space, you can take it out and use it.
これはずっと出してみたかったグッズなのでみんなに見てもらえると嬉しいです！
I've always wanted to make this merch, so I hope everyone loves it!
そして最後は、こちら！
And finally, this!
シチュエーションボイス「ライブの後で」。ちょっとおちゃめな私とこれからに向けて意気込みを語るかっこいい私の両方が楽しめるボイスです！
Situation Voice: "After the Live". Enjoy both my playful side and my cool side talking about future goals!
そして今回はフルセットの特典が2つあるよ！
And this time, there are two full-set purchase bonuses!
まずはこちら！ときのそら直筆サイン＋箔押し複製メッセージ入りチケット風カード！
First is this ticket-style card with a hand-signed autograph and foil-stamped message!
今回はですね、いつもなんですけど数量限定なしでやるので
This time, as always, there's no quantity limit,
ぜひみなさんたくさんたくさんサイン書かせてください！心を込めて全部書くからぜひぜひいっぱい応募してね！
so please let me write tons of autographs! I'll put my heart into every single one, so please apply!
そしてもう一つの特典はこちら！
And the other bonus is this!
hololive OFFICIAL CARD GAME PRカード hBD24-045「ときのそら」
Hololive Official Card Game PR Card hBD24-045 "Tokino Sora".
フルセットを購入した人だけの特別な推しホロメンカードです！
A special oshi holomember card exclusively for full-set purchasers!
まだ遊んだことないよって人、ホロライブオフィシャルカードゲームのホームページやカードの詳細や遊び方を確認できるからぜひチェックしてね！
If you haven't played yet, check out the official card game website for details and rules!
これでみんな勝ってくれるだろうな。勝ってくれよー！
I'm sure everyone will win with this. Make sure you win!
というわけで以上誕生日グッズでした！みんなよろしくね！
So those were the birthday goods! Thanks everyone!
そして2つ目のお知らせは、なんと！昨日、今日なのかな？の0時にデジタル配信が始まりました！
And the second announcement is... surprise! Digital streaming started at midnight yesterday... or today?
スワロウテイルのミュージックビデオ、なんとこのあとプレミア公開！
The music video for "Swallow Tail" will premiere right after this!
澄み渡る青は いつも始まりを強く照らすから
The clear blue sky always brightly illuminates the beginning,
本当は震えている手足が隠せないよ
I can't hide my trembling hands and feet.
みんな、みんなに感謝の気持ちを込めてMVを用意しておきました！
I prepared an MV with gratitude for everyone!
ぜひぜひみんなさんMVでも私の曲聴いてください！
Please, everyone, listen to my song in the MV too!
これが嬉しい告知だよー！
This is such a happy announcement!
この曲のテーマというか、爽やかな感じでみんなへの感謝の気持ちを込めつつ、ちょっと切ない歌詞もあったりするので、とてもMV発表がありますよということですね！
The theme of this song is refreshing, filled with gratitude for everyone, but also with some bittersweet lyrics, so I'm thrilled to announce this MV!
このあと21時15分からの予定なんですが、すごくギリギリかもしれない。
It's scheduled for 21:15 right after this, though it might be a tight schedule.
配信は21時半からになります。
The stream will start at 21:30.
よろしくお願いします！
Thank you for your support!
というわけで、その曲最後に聴きたくない？
So, wouldn't you like to hear that song at the very end?
初めて生で歌います。この曲で締めたいと思います。
I'll sing it live for the very first time. I'd like to close with this song.
聴いてください、「Swallow Tail」。
Please listen to "Swallow Tail".
澄み渡る青は いつも始まりを強く照らすから
The clear blue sky always brightly illuminates the beginning,
本当は震えている手足が隠せないよ
I can't hide my trembling hands and feet.
澄み渡る青は いつも始まりを強く照らすから
Clear blue skies always brightly illuminate the start,
本当は震えている手足が隠せないよ
So I can't hide my trembling hands and feet, though I truly am shaking.
物語の先は どう？ 君なら何色で描く？
What lies beyond this story? How will you paint it in what colors?
咽び泣いた日のこと やめられなかった日のことを
The days I choked back sobs, the days I couldn't stop from crying.
ツバメみたいに速く飛べたならいいのに
I wish I could fly as fast as a swallowtail.
もう何もいらないから 忘れさせないから
I need nothing more, and I won't let you forget.
どこまでも遠くへと このまま手を繋いで take a journey
Take a journey far away, holding hands just as we are.
涙泳ぐように 浅い闇を越えて
Cross over the pale darkness like a swimming tear,
いびつな翼で渡ろうよ 無限の夏の空へ
Let's cross with clumsy wings to the endless summer sky.
失くした鍵は見つかった？ 燃えるゴミの日に出しちゃった？
Did you find the lost key? Did you throw it out on burnable trash day?
いつの間にか芽吹いた 君のスペシャルな夢の船
Before you knew it, your special dream ship had sprouted wings.
子供みたいに青く願えたらいいのに
If only we could wish upon it as innocently as children,
気が付けば繭の中で
Before we knew it, we were trapped inside the cocoon.
胸の隅で疼いて泣くのは きっと大事なものだから
The reason it hurts and weeps in our chests must be because it's something precious.
間違っても彷徨っても 離さないでいようね
Even if we make mistakes or wander, let's never let go.
空の果て 群青のその先を見つめて
Gazing beyond the edge of the sky into the azure blue.
飛びたいこの命賭けて
Betting this life on the wish to fly.
もう何もいらないから 忘れさせないから
I need nothing more, and I won't let you forget.
どこまでも遠くへと ありのまま紡いで take a journey
Take a journey far away, spinning the story as it is.
涙泳ぐように 浅い闇を越えて
Cross over the pale darkness like a swimming tear,
いびつな翼でいいよ 行こう 無限の夏の空へ
It's fine to use clumsy wings, let's go to the endless summer sky.
胸の隅でいたんで 泣くのは きっと大事なものだから
Living in the corner of our chests, crying, is truly what matters most.
間違っても彷徨っても 離さないでいようよ
Even if we stray or wander, let's not let go, okay?
空の果て 遠くの その先を見つめて 飛びたいの この命 賭けて
Staring at the horizon beyond the azure sky, let's leap toward this life.
もう何もいらないから 忘れさせないから
I need nothing more, and I won't let you forget.
どこまでも遠くへと ありのまま紡いで take a journey
Take a journey far away, spinning the story as it is.
涙泳ぐように 浅い闇を越えて
Cross over the pale darkness like a swimming tear,
いびつな翼でいいよ 行こう
Let's go onwards with clumsy wings.
無限の夏の空へ
To the endless summer sky.